1. Filter streams
	InputStream and OutputStream are fairly raw classes. They merely read and write bytes singly or in groups
		Java provides a number of filter classes you can attach to raw streams to translate the raw bytes to and from these and other formats
	two versions of filters
		filter stream
			works primarily with raw data as bytes
		reader and writer
			handles the special case of text
	filters are organized in a chain, for example
		raw compressed, encrypted data from network	-TelnetInputStream-> 
		raw compressed, encrypted data			-BufferedInputStream(to speed up the whole process)->
		buffered, compressed, encrypted data		-CipherInputStream->
		buffered, compressed data			-GZIPInputStream-> 
		buffered data					-InputStreamReader(to convert the data into Unicode text)->
		text
	buffered streams
		the read() method of BufferedInputStream attampts to completely fill the array using as many times as necessary
			so you don't have to manually guarantee that!
	PrintStream
		System.out is a PrintStream
		constructors
			PrintStream(OutputStream out)
			PrintStream(OutputStream out, boolean autoFlush)
				by default, autoFlush is false
				if activated, the stream will be flushed every time a byte array or linefeed is written or a println() method is invoked
		methods
			print(..)
			println(..)
		but network programming should avoid PrintStream! because
			println() is platform dependent
				the line seperator you output from the server may not work on the client
			it assumes the default encoding of the platform on which it’s running
			PrintStream catches any exceptions thrown by the underlying output stream
				it's not good for the unreliable network connections
	data streams
		DataInputStream and DataOutputStream provide methods for reading and writing Java’s primitive data types and strings in a binary format
			primarily intended for exchanging data between two different Java programs through a network connection, a datafile, a pipe, or some other intermediary
		writeChars(String), writeBytes(String), writeUTF(String)
			writeChars() and writeBytes() do not include the length of the String, so the String cannot be distinguished from adjacent Strings or chars
			writeUTF() should only be use to send data to another Java program, since other language will not recognaize the String's length in it
			readUTF() is the complement of writeUTF()
				but there's no readChars() or readBytes(), you have to read them one at a time
	DigestInputStream
		used to generate a message digest of the data
		for example, generate a SHA digest based on the whole data
		      FileInputStream in = new FileInputStream(filename);
		      MessageDigest sha = MessageDigest.getInstance("SHA-256");
		      DigestInputStream din = new DigestInputStream(in, sha);
		      while (din.read() != -1) ;
		      din.close();
		      byte[] digest = sha.digest();

2. Reader and Writer
	an almost complete mirror of the input and output stream class hierarchy designed for working with characters instead of bytes
		the encoding varies
		has almost the same fundamental methods as InputStream and OutputStream
	InputStreamReader & OutputStreamWriter
		translate raw byte data to characters and vise versa
		constructor
			InputStreamReader(InputStream in, String encoding)
				data goes from the InputStream towards the Reader
				about encoding:
					read in some text, and interpret them with the specified encoding
					all the Strings in Java are UTF-16 of Unicode
			OutputStreamWriter(OutputStream out, String encoding)
				looks odd, but data does go from the Writer towards the OutputStream
				default encoding depends on the OS
				so it's better to specify the encoding every time
					OutputStreamWriter w = new OutputStreamWriter(
					    new FileOutputStream("OdysseyB.txt"), "Cp1253");
					w.write("ἦμος δ΄ ἠριγένεια φάνη ῥοδοδάκτυλος Ἠώς");
					System.out.println(w.getEncoding());		// return the encoding of the object
	raw readers that read characters without requiring an underlying input stream (complement writers exist)
		FileReader
		StringReader
		CharArrayReader
	Reader
		boolean ready()		similar to available(), but only finds out whether the reader may be read without blocking
	filter readers and writers
		BufferedReader & BufferedWriter
			String readLine()
			void newLine()		// insert a system-dependent line-separator string into the output
				// Because network protocols generally specify the required line terminator, you should not use this method for network programming
		PrintWriter
			replacement of PrintStream

3. threads
	two ways to give a thread something to do:
		subclass Thread and override run() method
		implement Runnable interface and pass the Runnable object to the Thread constructor
	passing data to and returning data from threads
		Because the signature of the run() method is fixed, you can’t pass arguments to it or return values from it. 
		pass data
			you can pass by constrcutor of Thread's subclass, or implementation of Runnable and save it as a field
		return information from a thread
			novices' solution
				store the result as a field in the Thread, then get it in the main()
				to assure the result is already there when you get, you have to keep checking in a loop, 
					which is wasted and may result in main thread taking all the CPU times and other threads having no time to process
			callback
				when finished, the thread calls a method of the main class which created it
					and pass the result as parameters
						public class C{
							public void receiveResult(int i){
								System.out.println(i);
							}
							public static void main(String[] args){
								new MyThead(new C).start();
								// when main thread ends, c won't be dump, because a reference of it is kept by MyThread
							}
						}
						class MyThread extends Thread{
							private C c;
							public MyThread(C c){
								this.c = c;
							}
							public void run(){
								c.receiveResult(1);
							}
						}
						// receiveResult() runs in the MyThread thread instead of main thread, so there's no racing
				However, starting threads in a constructor is dangerous, especially threads that will call back to the originating object. 
					There’s a race condition here that may allow the new thread to call back before the constructor is finished and the object is fully initialized
				if there're many objects intersted in the result
					create an interface, containing the receiveResult() method, so that all the object implements this interface will have this method
					create a method in MyThread, objects call it to register itself
				Swing, AWT and JabaBeans use this pattern to handle events!
					components register themselves to the event-handling thread by add a listener
					it's called the Observer design pattern!!
	main thread is a just an ordinary thread! it may end before other threads. 
		The process will end when all threads end
	difference between sleep() and yield()
		yield() let the thread give away CPU, and immediately enter the ready queue
			if there are threads with equal or higher priority, they will gain the CPU
			otherwise, the original thread itself will regain CPU
		sleep() ceases the thread for certain amount of time
			if no other thread is waiting, CPU will be idle
	Futures, Callables, and Executors
		a new approach to make it easier to handle callbacks by hiding the details
		The advantage is that you can spawn off many different threads, then get the answers you need in the order you need them
		how?
			create an ExecutorService that will create threads for you as needed
			submit Callable jobs to the ExecutorService and for each one you get back a Future
			ask the Future for the result of the job
				If the result is ready, you get it immediately. 
				If it’s not ready, the polling thread blocks until it is ready
		example
			class MyTask implements Callable<Integer> {
			  @Override
			  public Integer call() {
			    // do the job here
			    return 1;
			  }
			}
			public class Main {
			  public static void main(String[] args) {
			    // split the job into 2 pieces
			    MyTask task1 = new MyTask();
			    MyTask task2 = new MyTask();

			    // spawn 2 threads
			    ExecutorService service = Executors.newFixedThreadPool(2);

			    Future<Integer> future1 = service.submit(task1);	// service.execute(new Runnable(){}) can start a Runnable, but no callback as Future
			    Future<Integer> future2 = service.submit(task2);

			    System.out.println(future1.get() + future2.get());
			  }
			}

